http://www.instituteforlegalreform.com

×
You copied the event url to the clipboard
Who We Are
America has the world’s costliest legal system, and 79% of American voters see the number of “frivolous” lawsuits as a problem. The Institute for Legal Reform is addressing these key issues in order to achieve a fair legal system that promotes economic growth and opportunity.
Explore our issues by state or by issue title
Issues
America has the most costly legal system in the world according to an ILR study, and 87% of American voters view the number of “meritless” lawsuits in the country as a problem. To be sure, the American legal system is complex, and the abuses are occurring on many levels. Please explore our Issues Section to learn more about the various issues impacting our legal system and what ILR is doing to advance reform on many fronts.
State
State
Alabama
Alaska
Arizona
Arkansas
California
Colorado
Data Privacy
False Claims Act (FCA)
Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA)
International Initiatives
Lawsuit Lending
Mass Tort Multidistrict Litigation
Medical Liability
Municipality Litigation
Other Issues
Over-Enforcement
Securities Litigation Reform
State Attorneys General
Telephone Consumer Protection Act (TCPA)
Third Party Litigation Funding (TPLF)
Transnational
Trial Lawyer Advertising
EU Lawmakers Pass Union-Wide Class Action Directive
The European Parliament approved a new union-wide collective action (or class action) directive last week.
News
In the News
Feature
December 7, 2020
ICYMI: Despite Pandemic, Law Firms Are Filing More Tort Cases
According to a recent report in Law.com, the COVID-19 pandemic hasn’t stopped lawyers from filing tort lawsuits. The report found that tort lawsuits filed in federal courts are increasing, with most of the cases stemming from the pandemic.   Lex Machina’s first “Torts Litigation Report,” released last week, looks at filings from 2010 through Sept. 30, 2020. After a […]
View All News
Read More
News
In The News Today- December 10, 2020
COVID-19 Liability
News
Australia Should Brace For An Increase In Lawsuits If Third Party Litigation Funders Are Deregulated.
International Initiatives, Third Party Litigation Funding (TPLF)
News
In The News Today- December 8, 2020
Telephone Consumer Protection Act (TCPA)
News
Opinion: PA Gov’s liability protections veto leaves industries “in the cold”
COVID-19 Liability
News
In The News Today- December 7, 2020
COVID-19 Liability
Sign Up. To sign up to receive our email with updates on Legal Reform, please begin filling out our form on left. When you hit submit, you consent to our processing of the personal data you provide us with. Thank you.
Subscribe to Our Newsletter
Get updates from ILR delivered straight to your inbox. Sign up today!Name
First
Email
What Newsletters Are You Interested In?
Research & Exclusive Events
Daily News Alerts
Weekly News Alerts
Research
Featured Research
The Institute for Legal Reform shines a light on what is wrong in the legal system. We conduct cutting-edge research and advance pragmatic solutions. We then tirelessly advocate for those solutions with Congress, state legislatures, federal regulators, international policymakers and the courts to effect meaningful change.
01
The Future of AI Liability in the EU: Protecting Consumers Without Stifling Innovation
02
Fairer, Faster, Better II: An Empirical Assessment of Consumer Arbitration
03
Tort Liability Costs for Small Businesses
04
ILR Briefly COVID-19 Series: Public Nuisance at the Door
View All Research
Who We Are
America has the world’s costliest legal system, and 79% of American voters see the number of “frivolous” lawsuits as a problem. The Institute for Legal Reform is addressing these key issues in order to achieve a fair legal system that promotes economic growth and opportunity.
Explore our issues by state or by issue title
Issues
America has the most costly legal system in the world according to an ILR study, and 87% of American voters view the number of “meritless” lawsuits in the country as a problem. To be sure, the American legal system is complex, and the abuses are occurring on many levels. Please explore our Issues Section to learn more about the various issues impacting our legal system and what ILR is doing to advance reform on many fronts.
State
State
Alabama
Alaska
Arizona
Arkansas
California
Colorado
Data Privacy
False Claims Act (FCA)
Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA)
International Initiatives
Lawsuit Lending
Mass Tort Multidistrict Litigation
Medical Liability
Municipality Litigation
Other Issues
Over-Enforcement
Securities Litigation Reform
State Attorneys General
Telephone Consumer Protection Act (TCPA)
Third Party Litigation Funding (TPLF)
Transnational
Trial Lawyer Advertising
Issues
America has the most costly legal system in the world according to an ILR study, and 79% of American voters view the number of “meritless” lawsuits in the country as a problem. To be sure, the American legal system is complex, and the abuses are occurring on many levels. Please explore our Issues Section to learn more about the various issues impacting our legal system and what ILR is doing to advance reform on many fronts.
Arbitration
Asbestos
Data Privacy
False Claims Act (FCA)
Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA)
Lawsuit Lending
Medical Liability
Over-Enforcement
Securities Litigation Reform
State Attorneys General
Telephone Consumer Protection Act (TCPA)
Third Party Litigation Funding (TPLF)
View All Issues
Get Updates on Legal Reform Delivered Straight to Your Email
To sign up to receive our email with updates on Legal Reform, fill in the following fields. When you hit submit, you consent to our processing of the personal data you provide us with. Thanks and welcome.
Before submitting your personal data, please take a look at our Privacy Notice: General Privacy Notice or EU Privacy Notice. You can also contact us at privacy@uschamber.com.
What Newsletter Are You Interested In?
Research & Exclusive Events
Daily News Alerts
Weekly News Alerts
Name
First
Last
TitleOrganizationPhoneEmail Address
CommentsThis field is for validation purposes and should be left unchanged.
What do we use cookies for?
We use cookies and similar technologies to recognize your repeat visits and preferences, as well as to measure the effectiveness of campaigns and analyze traffic. To learn more about cookies, including how to disable them, view our Cookie Policy. By clicking "I Accept" or "X" on this banner, or using our site, you consent to the use of cookies unless you have disabled them.
I Accept
GDPR
×
In respecting GDPR regulations we can't allow you to submit this form without accepting our privacy policy conditions.
Close
Accept Privacy Policy
